here's the thing there won't be a gaijin
if the data we have already is for real
and you know one can always discover
that there's a problem at the level of
the data that you're not in a position
no but assuming that the data is what we
think it is there won't be a gaijin can
there be gay genetic influences sure
that could be but there are patterns
that are simply inconsistent with a gay
gene and what's more I don't think the
questions are insurmountable as to
whether or not a gay gene could
propagate evolutionarily but it's not a
simple question of how they would but in
any case the to build the protection of
homosexuals on the idea that there is
simply no environmental influence and
therefore as you argue in the book that
effectively it would be immoral to hold
people responsible for something over
which they had no control that's not a
sound foundation now it may be that
people have very little choice
especially here we're gonna step on a
big landmine okay or I am you go first
okay at least for males there is likely
to be not very much choice because the
switch will have been flipped very early
right so in any case we don't need a gay
gene in order to fully support the
argument for compassion and
understanding but it was a useful crutch
before we had enough information to know
what was going on and people are
understandably reluctant to give it up
yeah by the way the landmine you just
deftly deftly tripped over it without
least one ones the fascinates me because
I say to everyone who complains about
what I'm saying about gay bit that when
I say look it maybe it's a bit more
maybes a bit more mellifluous even after
a certain stage than we pretend
and that a gay isn't necessarily as I
say a one-way street even the people who
object to that deeply concede I might be
onto something in the case of female
lesbianism right well cuz it's
definitely more there's definitely more
adaptability there than there is among
male homosexuals but I mean for instance
I mean you do sometimes there are some
lesbians who have had horrible
experiences with men or had a terrible
husband or worse and they end up falling
in love with a woman I do not know of
any case with a man who's married to the
most horrible woman and as a result
starts to screw around with men I just
you know as a straight guy it's hard for
me to imagine a woman that horrible but
that's it I'm leaving you I'm gonna be a
local gay bar as a result yep but I mean
if you think about it look the reason
that this should be more flexible on the
lesbian side is staring us in the face
it's just obvious as you said it's not
that hard
gay men have a really and you know again
among the many amazing points that you
make in this book that I've never heard
anybody else say but you know we're
begging for an exploration gay men have
a problem producing babies the mythology
of the moment may be that they don't but
you know Monty Python correctly nailed
the fact that a pair of men don't have a
uterus you know and therefore that
invites questions about how it's going
to be done women don't have this problem
in fact a lesbian couple has a couple of
uterus right what that means is that
there is an opportunity here let's just
do this straightforwardly in an
evolutionary sense human babies are
extremely expensive to raise and they
are much better raised when people team
up right so a straight partnership is a
team and its primary objective
is the successful raising a baby's the
production of resources the nurturing
the delivery of information on how to be
a successful human a single individual
has a problem raising a baby there's
just not enough labor it's too
labor-intensive a pair of lesbians has
the labor and the uterus is what they
lack is a single cell right all they
need is a single cell to trigger a baby
and then everything else they've got
right now there are plenty of ways that
history can deliver a circumstance in
which there aren't enough men around
for example warfare warfare will
eliminate men from the map are we really
to imagine that evolution will take a
bunch of people who are perfectly
capable of raising offspring and
sideline them from that most
fundamentally Darwinian objective
because there aren't enough men around
for people to pair off oh no that's not
how it's going to work
surely people who have everything
necessary to produce offspring of their
own will team up and do so especially if
all they need in order to trigger the
process is a single cell they'll find
one right and so the point is lesbian
couples make perfect evolutionary sense
in many circumstances and that would
mean that the ability to facultative ly
go in that direction at the point that
it becomes a viable path forward should
be there as a contingency plan built-in
to women we can't make the same argument
for men at some point I will make an
argument for the evolutionary nature of
male homosexuality but I'm not ready to
deploy it in public just yet I have to
say I do want you to do that bread all
right well you know I lay down that
Chinese slightly in the book I say look
the evolutionary biologists have been
ducking this one for a long time now yes
ducking notice there's plenty of room
under the table here for me to to duck
if I must all right so where were we we
were talking about the understandable
desire
amongst people who feel that they have
something personal at stake to avoid
certain kinds of exploration and then
others of us find those explorations are
necessary even to the very protection at
the focus of that concern right I would
say gay people are far safer if we
explore this carefully then if we
pretend the issue is simpler than it is